第二修正案（允许佩戴武器）不仅很过时 而且很危险
The Second Amendment isn`t just obsolete. It`s dangerous.
我完全明白你为什么这么想
I totally get why you think that.
抱歉 我之前还从不知道有谁会喜欢枪
I`m sorry, I`ve just never known someone who`s into guns before.
我不喜欢枪 瑞秋
I`m not into guns, Rachel.
我只有一些
I have a couple.
不止一把吧
More than the one.
那也不能说明我是狂热分子
That doesn`t mean that I`m a fanatic.
这也不代表我不支持管制
Okay, it doesn`t mean that I`m not for restrictions.
等待期和背景审查
and waiting periods and background checks.
那你是什么意思 安迪
So what does it mean, Andy?
我只想保护自己
I just wanna be able to protect myself.
要保护自己免受谁的伤害
From what, exactly?
你在谷歌上调查过我
You googled me.
是的
Yeah, I did.
该死的因特网
Fucking Internet.
你有一段很黑暗的过去
You have a very dark past.
是的
Yeah.
那你为什么不告诉我
So why didn`t you tell me?
因为我喜欢你
Because I like you.
我不想把你吓跑
I didn`t wanna scare you away.
我6岁的时候
I was six.
我的保姆被谋杀了
My babysitter was murdered.
还有我的老师和社工
Along with my teacher and my caseworker.
这些年来还有其他37个人
and 37 other people over the years…
这还只是我知道的
That I`m aware of.
没人抓住凶手吗
And they never caught him?
只能说 正义得到了伸张
Put it this way, justice was done.
- 等等 - 尝尝这个
- Wait! - Play with this.
听着 安迪
Look, Andy,
你是个好人 但这些对我来说有点过了
I think you`re a nice guy, but, uh, this is just too much for me.
我能理解
I get it.
我得走了
I should go.
我猜今晚又只剩你和我了
I guess it`s just me and you again tonight, pal.
给我吸一口 好吗
Give me a hit off that, will you?
你想玩玩吗
You wanna play?
那就来玩吧
Let`s play.
瑞秋呢
What about Rachel?
她不想玩了吗
Didn`t she wanna play?
我们再也不会知道她是不是天然的红发了
Now we`ll never know if she`s a natural redhead.
面对现实吧 安迪
Face it, Andy.
我才是你的全部
I`m all you`ve got.
有时候 在周五晚上
Sometimes, it`s nice, just hanging out on a Friday night.
和你最好的朋友一起玩也挺不错的
with your best friend.
操你妈的
Fuck you!
《鬼娃回魂7》
（当地女性杀害五人）
（唯一幸存者 爱丽丝·皮尔斯 7岁）
（出生地：美国 普罗维登斯）
再来一次
Again.
你说过她瘫痪了
I thought you said she was paralyzed.
是的
She is.
那是因为电流
That`s just the juice.
看到了吗
See?
她腰部以下没有任何知觉
From the waist down, she`s a pincushion.
好吧 够了
All right, that`s enough.
我仍然能在我的噩梦里
I can still see him.
看见他
in my nightmares.
他扭曲的脸孔 惊悚的笑容
His twisted face, that horrible laugh,
他刀子的反光 还有受害者的哀嚎
the glint off his blade, the screams of his victims.
谁的受害者 妮卡
Whose victims, Nica?
那些谋杀都是真的
The murders were real.
你知道的
You know that.
但恰克却不是真的
But Chucky never was.
没错
That`s right.
他是幻想出来的
He was a fantasy.
一种幻觉
A delusion.
他只是我的一个面具 以便我能面对我自己
He was a mask I wore so I could go on looking in the mirror,
这样我才能接受我犯下的罪行
SO I could live with myself.
现在你看镜子时 会看到什么
And now, when you look in the mirror, what do you see?
我不看了
I don`t look.
如果你想学会接受自己 你就必须如此
You`ll have to, if you`re ever gonna learn to forgive yourself.
妮卡 你已经进步很多了
Nica, you`ve made tremendous progress.
在过去的四年 你接受了
In the past four years, you`ve had to accept.
许多关于自己的残酷现实
some hard truths about yourself.
你很勇敢
That is very brave.
我为你感到骄傲
I`m proud of you.
（哈罗盖特精神病院）
我要把你转移到哈罗盖特精神病院
I`m having you transferred to Harrogate.
妮卡 那是中等戒备的医院
That`s medium security, Nica.
这意味着你有跟多的隐私和自由
That means more privacy, more independence, more freedom,
当然 是在合理范围内的
within reason, of course…
弗利医生 我做的事情不可原谅
Dr. Foley, what I did was unforgivable.
精神分裂是一种病
Schizophrenia is an illness.
根据其定义 依照法律
By definition, and according to the law,
你不对你的行为负责
you weren`t responsible for your actions.
你觉得艾莉丝能因为这个理由
Do you think Alice would accept that.
而原谅我让她成为孤儿吗
as an apology for making her an orphan?
没有监控吗
Are there no cameras?
中等戒备的医院里没有监控
Not in medium security.
但也不能肆意妄为
But don`t abuse the privilege.
浴室在后面
Bathroom`s back there.
淋浴是面对残疾人设计的 但你也可以叫艾希莉或帕姆帮你
Shower`s handicap-friendly, but if you need help, ask for Ashley or Pam.
她们轮流值班
They alternate days.
需要什么 就叫我
Anything else, just let me know.
我叫卡洛斯
My name`s Carlos.
谢谢你对我这么好
Thanks for being so nice.
别误会 我并不喜欢你
Don`t misunderstand. I`m not a fan.
我们不会变成朋友 我只是在尽我的责任
We`re not gonna be friends. I`m just doing my job.
好吧 还是谢谢你
Well, thank you anyway.
不客气
You`re welcome.
你出过事故吗
You in an accident?
我生来就是残疾
I was born like this.
我丈夫有多发性硬化症
My husband has MS.
抱歉
I`m sorry.
我不会让这妨碍他去生活
I don`t let it keep him from living his life.
弗利医生 二号房间需要你的帮助
Dr. Foley, your assistance is needed in room two.
请弗利医生赶往二号房间
Dr. Foley to room two, please.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
你能看见我吗
Can you see me?
是的
Yeah.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
其他人都看不到我
None of the others can see me.
别害怕
Please don`t be afraid.
我不害怕你
I`m not afraid of you.
太棒了
Good.
我不会伤害你
I won`t hurt you.
我只想找个人说说话
I just need someone to talk to.
我在这里度过了一生
I spent my whole life here.
然后我死了
Then I died.
就在这房间
Right here in this room…
很久 很久以前
A long, long time ago.
那可真糟
That`s awful.
安吉拉 我们都能看见你
Angela, we can all see you.
去你的
Fuck you!
现在去骚扰别人吧
Go haunt somebody else now.
她没有恶意
Ah. she`s harmless.
大概30年前 他们发现她住在街上
They found her living on the street, like, 30 years ago,
死亡往往比无家可归更引人注意
but I guess being dead`s more exotic than being homeless.
我不太明白
I don`t know about that.
如果之前没死 仅仅是无家可归的话
Well, I`ve never been dead before, but I have been homeless,
那还真是无趣的
and it`s pretty fucking colorless.
我是迈克尔
I`m Michael.
妮卡
Nica.
你想要
Do you wanna, uh…
你的口香糖哪来的
Where did you get the gum?
卡洛斯给我的
Oh, um, Carlos.
卡洛斯
Carlos?
你一定给他留下了不错的印象
You must have made quite the impression.
并没有
Not really.
他相当的严厉
No, he`s kind of a hard-ass.
但艾希莉护士 她是我的守护天使
But Nurse Ashley, she`s my guardian angel.
如果不是她 我可能还在戒毒所
Wasn`t for her, I`d still be in detox.
你是转院过来的
So, uh, you just transferred?
是的
Yup.
从哪来的
Where from?
洛克莫尔
Lochmoor.
你就是那个女孩
you`re that girl who…
是的
Yeah.
你还喜欢红头发吗
You still have a thing for redheads?
什么
What?
因为这个 那个 你 不是吗
Because the… This, you… No.
抱歉 问得太早了
Oh. Sorry. That`s too soon.
我可以和你换香烟
I`ll trade you for a cigarette.
好
Okay.
黄箭口香糖
Juicy Fruit.
为什么你要这么做 克莱尔
So why`d you do it? Claire.
我们都想问呢 对吧
We`re all wondering the same thing here, right?
让她缓一会 她还是新人
Give her a break, okay? She`s new.
去他的
Fuck that!
如果我要和某个屠杀了全家的
If I`m gonna be living down the hallway.
疯子住在同一层
from someone who butchered her whole family,
我有权知道她会因为什么起杀意
I have a right to know what set her off.
那为什么你把房子烧了
Well, why`d you burn your house down?
你总提这件事
You always bring that up.
我的意思是 如果我们要互相指责的话
I`m just saying, if we`re pointing fingers here, then…
我可没杀人
I didn`t kill anyone.
妮卡也没杀人
Neither did Nica.
是恰奇干的
Chucky did it.
我不怪你因为我做的事害怕
I don`t blame you for being afraid after what I did.
我当时病得很重
I was very ill.
你现在好点了吗
Are you feeling better now?
我理解你的担心 当然我们应该谈一谈
I understand your concerns, and, absolutely, we should talk about it,
但相信我 妮卡不对任何人造成威胁
but, believe me, Nica isn`t a danger to anyone anymore.
别忘记 她不是唯一一位
And let`s not forget, she isn`t the only one.
因为精神失常而脱罪的人
here to benefit from an insanity plea.
不过她是唯一的连环杀人凶手
She`s the only multiple murderer, though.
是屠杀 事实上
Mass murderer, actually.
二者是有区别的
There`s a difference.
有什么大不了 我们都有病
Who cares? We`re all sick.
我只想知道她为什么杀了他们
I wanna know why she killed them.
我病态地嫉妒我的妹妹
I was pathologically jealous of my sister,
我对我的侄女艾莉丝占有欲太强
and I was always too possessive of Alice, who is my niece.
她现在12岁 但我再也见不到她了
She`s 12 now, and I`ll never see her again.
希望她过得还好
I only hope she`s doing okay.
她过得并不好
She`s not okay.
你说什么
Excuse me?
恰奇说的
Chucky told me.
安吉拉
Angela.
他给我
He called me.
打电话了
On the phone.
他让我告诉你他要来找你
He said to tell you he`s coming for you…
鉴于你现在可以见外来访客了
Now that you can have visitors.
你觉得这很有趣吗
You think this is funny?
不
No.
并不
I don`t.
没关系 安吉
It`s okay, Angie.
别害怕
It`s okay.
好吧 这事被重提也是无法避免的
Okay, it was inevitable that this would come up.
重要的是我们要一起讨论解决
And it`s important that we all explore it together as a group.
我想我有个东西能够帮上忙
I think I have something that will help.
你们好 我是恰奇 想一起玩吗
Hi, I`m Chucky. Wanna play?
这只是 只是个好家伙公司的玩偶
Is that a… It`s just a Good Guy doll,
80年代造的一千个中的一个
one of thousands made back in the 80s.
不 他说自己叫恰奇
No, he said, Chucky!
他们有50个不同的名字 百分之二的娃娃都叫恰奇
They had 50 different names. Two percent of them were Chucky.
你的意思是说这是巧合吗
You`re saying it`s a coincidence?
并不是 我特意买的恰奇
Not at all. I paid for a Chucky.
你从哪买的
Wher&d you get it?
在热门话题买的
Hot Topic.
妮卡 这不会让你不适吧
Nica, this doesn`t make you uncomfortable, does it?
一点也不
No, not at all.
天啊
Oh, my God.
怎么了 玛德琳
What is it, Madeleine?
他是我的孩子
He`s my baby.
张开嘴 亲爱的
Open up, sweetheart.
小火车开过来啦
Here comes the choo-choo.
太烫了
It`s too hot for him.
我喜欢有人抱我
I like to be hugged.
不敢相信他已经开始说话了
I can`t believe he`s talking already!
玛德琳 别吓唬人了
Madeleine, stop it!
你孩子死了 你明明知道
Your baby is dead. You know that.
你有什么毛病 就不能让她高兴一会吗
What is your problem? Why can`t you just let her be happy?
这样能让她开心吗
You think that`s the way to make her happy?
让她和变态杀手的战利品玩过家家
Letting her play house with some psycho killer`s trophy?
- 把他还回去 - 他
- Give him back. - Him?
这个人称代词用得好
That`s an interesting choice of pronoun.
你现在还是是无法将现实
Are you still having trouble separating reality.
和脑子里的幻觉区分吗
from that sick shit in your head?
不
No.
不幸的是 现在 在我面前呈现地很清楚
Unfortunately, these days, reality is painfully clear.
把他还回去
Now give him back.
你要怎么做 妮卡
What are you gonna do, Nica?
砍我吗 割我的喉咙吗
You gonna stab me? Cut my throat?
砍掉我的头吗
Chop off my head?
别瞎扯了
Don`t be ridiculous.
我们连真的餐具都用不上
We don`t even have access to real cutlery.
我唯一能拿到的东西
The only thing I could get my hands on.
是他们每天早上给我的巴比妥
are the barbiturates they give me every morning.
我已经存了好几个月了
that I`ve been stockpiling for months,
等待着有天对哪个臭婊子下毒
waiting for the right bitch to come along to poison.
给
Here.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 没事 - 你还好吗 恰奇
- Sure. - Are you okay, Chucky?
对了 我叫马克
I`m Mark, by the way.
很高兴见到你 我听说了你很多事
It`s nice to meet you. I`ve heard a lot about you.
什么
What?
迈克尔说的
From Michael.
他现在在泳池训练 为2020年奥林匹克做准备
He`s in the pool right now, getting ready for Tokyo in 2020,
别告诉别人
but don`t tell anyone.
迈克尔·菲尔普斯吗
Michael Phelps?
他退役了
He`s retired.
天 太尴尬了
God, this is embarrassing.
我最讨厌犯病了
I fucking hate it when this happens,
尤其是在美女面前
especially around a pretty girl.
这是我病发的诱因之一
It`s actually one of my triggers.
他的真名叫马尔科姆
His real name is Malcolm.
我们叫他多重马尔科姆
We call him Multiple Malcolm.
没人那么叫我
Nobody calls me that.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
妮卡 有人找你
Nica, you have a visitor.
妮卡 这位是瓦伦丁女士 你侄女的合法监护人
Nica, this is Ms. Valentine, your niece`s legal guardian.
你是艾莉丝的监护人吗
You`re Alice`s guardian?
没错
That`s right.
抱歉 但你似乎很面熟
I`m sorry, but you seem really familiar.
有没有人告诉你 你长得和珍妮弗·提莉一模一样
Did anyone ever tell you, you look exactly like Jennifer Tilly?
经常有人说
Yeah, I get that a lot.
你和我想象得也不太一样
You`re not quite what I expected, either.
你想象的是什么样
What did you expect?
身高再高点
Somebody taller.
你看着不危险
You don`t seem very dangerous.
你看着也不像当妈的
You don`t seem very motherly.
她怎么样了
How is she?
她死了 皮尔斯小姐
She`s dead, Miss Pierce.
什么
What?
瓦伦丁小姐 你之前告诉我就好了
Ms. Valentine, I wish you had told me.
我没说吗
Oh, didn`t I?
我真的很抱歉
Uh, I`m terribly sorry.
我只是因为她的死有些难过的反应不过来
I`ve just been going through an awful ordeal.
但她现在肯定在更好的地方
But she`s in a better place now, I know it.
发生了什么
What happened?
我不是医生 皮尔斯小姐 但我想应该是伤心致死
I`m no doctor, Miss Pierce, but I think it was a broken heart.
她想让我交给你样东西
She wanted you to have something.
你好 我是恰克 想一起玩吗
Hi, I'm Chucky, want to play?
- 这不是同一个 - 不是
- That`s not the same… - No, no.
这是他们在艾莉丝的心理辅导上用的
This is the doll that they used in Alice`s therapy.
帮助她摆脱过去
To help her get over the past.
她觉得这个也许对你有用
She thought that maybe it would help you, too.
给
There you go.
真可爱
That`s so sweet.
真谢谢你
Well, thank you so much.
祝你好运
Good luck.
我不要
I can`t…
妮卡在哪
Where`s Nica?
右手边最后一间
Last door on the right.
你能看到我
You can see me.
是的 我看得见你
Yeah, I can see you.
别害怕
Don`t be afraid.
什么
What?
我不会伤害你
I`m not going to hurt you.
你在耍我吗
You fucking with me?
没有
No.
没耍你
I`m not.
说实话 我很愿意有人陪着
Tell you the truth, I`m happy to have the company,
即使你不是真的
even if you aren`t real.
我给你解释一下
Okay, let me explain something to you.
我是个80年代大批生产的古董娃娃
I am a vintage, mass-marketed children`s toy from the 80s,
站在你面前
standing right in front of you,
拿着非常锋利的手术刀
holding a very sharp scalpel.
才不是
No, you`re not.
我就是
Yes, I am.
我是精神分裂患者
I`m a schizophrenic.
我会出现幻觉
I see things.
你是昨天晚上和我通话的那个疯女人吗
Aren`t you the crazy bitch I talked to last night on the phone?
有时候我也会幻听
Sometimes I hear things, too.
女士 够了
Okay, lady, you know what?
下一个就找你
You`re next.
我一会回来
I`m gonna be right back.
天啊
Jesus!
全都是疯子
Fucking cuckoo`s nest.
拜拜
Bye.
弗利医生 请到前台来
Dr. Foley, please report to the front desk.
该起床了 妮卡
Time to get up, Nica.
七点多了
It`s after 7:00.
起来
Come on!
（别着急）
好了
Okay.
给
Here you go.
谢了
Thanks.
我给你拿点水
I`ll get you some water.
不用管
Leave it! I…
抱歉 能不能让我一个人待会 拜托
Sorry. Could I just… Could I have some privacy, please?
我想换个衣服
I`d like to get dressed.
好吧
Okay.
急救警报
Code blue!
（恰克做的）
巴克利先生 我现在特别忙
Mr. Barclay, I`m extremely busy.
我们可不是在耍猴
We`re not running a circus here,
能不能有话直说
so could you please just get to the point?
演得不错 巴克雷
That`s very clever, Mr. Barclay.
真像那回事
Very convincing.
什么 不要
What? No!
他还活着 看看他
He`s alive. Just look at him.
你应该去拍电影
You should get a job in the movies.
我要见妮卡·皮尔斯
I wanna see Nica Pierce.
能否送巴克雷先生出去
Could you please show Mr. Barclay out?
我告诉你 不是她干的
I`m telling you, she didn`t do it!
快点 我们走
Come on. Let`s go.
再看一遍
Let`s watch it again.
真是百看不厌
That one just never gets old.
帮个忙 恰奇
Do me a favor, Chucky.
闭上你的臭嘴
Keep your fucking mouth shut.
你猜怎么的 安迪
You know what, Andy?
万一你真的疯了呢
What if you really are crazy?
你没想过吗
Have you ever thought of that?
也许你应该和尼卡一样进精神病院
Maybe you belong in the booby hatch with Nica.
也许这真的是你脑中幻想的
Maybe this really is just all in your head.
妮卡 不是你的错
Nica, it wasn`t your fault.
扯淡
Bullshit.
克莱尔 别这样
Claire, please.
我照顾了那女人五年
I took care of that woman for the past five years.
我给她洗头 擦屁股
I washed her hair. I wiped her ass.
我还听她说疯话到凌晨3点
I listened to her crazy until 3:00 in the morning.
她是我的朋友
She was my friend.
如果她想自杀 我肯定会知道
If she was thinking about killing herself, I`d have known it.
不一定
Not necessarily.
是妮卡做的
Nica did it!
她在安吉拉的血里她留下了自己的签名
She left her fucking calling card in Angela`s blood!
安吉拉是自杀
Angela did that.
她为什么要那么做
Why would she do that?
打扰一下
Excuse me.
我们是不是忽略了另外一个可能性
Aren`t we overlooking one other possibility?
不 我不那么认为
No, I don`t think we are.
克莱尔 你还没受够被人误会吗
Claire, don`t you ever get tired of being wrong?
还没
No, I do not!
奥卡姆剃刀
Occam`s razor.
最简单的解释通常就是对的解释
The simplest explanation is usually the right one.
恰奇干的
Chucky did it.
很抱歉我们来晚了
I`m so sorry we`re late.
不敢相信他们已经开始挖安吉拉的坟了
I can`t believe they`re digging Angela`s grave already.
等下 现在有两个娃娃了吗
Wait a minute, there`s two of them?
这娃娃真丑
What an ugly doll.
嗨 我是恰奇 想一起玩吗
Hi, I`m Chucky. Wanna play?
他是哪来的
Where the hell did he come from?
艾莉丝送的
From Alice.
她监护人带来的
From her guardian.
她叫什么来着
What did that woman say her name was?
瓦伦丁
Valentine.
天啊
Oh, my God.
蒂凡尼·瓦伦丁
Tiffany Valentine.
那是查尔斯·李·雷的女友
That was Charles Lee Ray`s girlfriend.
- 查尔斯·李·雷 - 那是谁
- Charles Lee Ray? - Who is that?
他是80年代的连环杀手
He was a serial killer in the 80s.
他在玩具店被开枪打死之前杀了22个人
He murdered 22 people before they shot him in a toy store.
他就死在好家伙玩偶的旁边
He died right next to a Good Guy doll.
查尔斯·李·雷的昵称就是恰奇
Charles Lee Ray`s nickname was Chucky.
别再让她
Please tell me that you are not gonna let her.
用一派胡言鼓动人心了
dominate the group with this crap.
妮卡 它只是个娃娃
Nica, it`s just a doll.
- 那就证明出来 - 什么
- Then prove it. - What?
在这里证明它只是个娃娃
Right here to everybody in this room, prove that it`s just a doll.
好吧
All right.
- 接着烧 - 太荒谬了
- Not yet. - Oh, this is ridiculous.
- 等下 换另一个 - 妮卡
- Wait a minute, now him. - Nica.
没准他俩调换了
He could`ve switched places with it somehow.
别烦我的孩子
You leave my baby alone.
麦蒂
Maddy.
等等
Wait!
你在做什么
What are you doing?
我以为已经讨论过了
I thought we were way past this.
我想错了
Iwas wrong.
它不是
Yeah, about him.
但另一个呢
But what about the other one?
我们去消灭他吧
Let`s just go and get rid of him. Okay?
以防万一 对吧
Better safe than sorry, that`s what I say.
他有机会的时候为什么没杀你
So why didn`t he kill you when he had the chance?
因为他想折磨我
Because he`s fucking with me.
这是他的作风
That`s what he does.
首先 他会把这里的人一个个杀掉
First, he`ll kill each and every one of you.
以你能想到最残忍的方法
in the most horrible ways you can imagine.
然后他会让我看着
And he`ll make me watch.
最后也把我杀掉
And then he`ll kill me, too.
又或者 我只是个疯子这一切都是我想象的
Unless, of course, I`m a complete psychopath.
还是往好的方面想吧
Well, let`s just stay positive.
玛德琳
Madeleine!
玛德琳去哪了
Where`s Madeleine going?
她带孩子出门散步了
She took her baby out for a walk.
你还是别烦她了
And I think you should leave her alone.
你必须去找她
You have to go get her.
不行
No, I can`t.
为什么不行
Why not?
我的户外权限被取消了
My outdoor privileges were suspended.
我侵入过弗利医生的电脑
I hacked into Dr. Foley`s computer.
特别简单
It was ridiculously easy,
比当市值两千亿公司的首席执行官简单多了
a lot easier than being CEO of a $200 billion corporation.
你现在又是马克·扎克伯格了
You`re Mark Zuckerberg now.
是啊
Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
我去搞定艾希莉
I`ll take care of Ashley.
好吧 但我必须说 这注意不太妙
Okay, fine, but, for the record, I think this is a bad idea.
打扰一下
I`m sorry.
能帮我一下吗 我不太熟悉这个轮椅
Can you help me with this? I`m not used to this chair.
- 没问题 - 谢谢
- Sure. - Thanks.
在这里 有东西卡住了
It`s just right over here. I think there`s something stuck.
就在这
Yeah, it`s right in here.
好
Okay.
我靠 克莱尔
Holy shit. Claire?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
福利博士 都是真的
Dr. Foley, it`s true.
他是活的
He`s alive.
这次你又对你自己做了什么
What have you done to yourself now?
什么 不 是他咬的
What? No! It was him!
克莱尔 跟我们走一趟
Claire, why don`t you come with us?
- 来吧 - 不
- Come on. - No.
不 是他做的 是他做的
No, it was him. It was him!
克莱尔
Claire.
不 不是的
No! No! No!
快停下
Stop!
不 让我走
No! Let me go!
不是的 傻逼快放开我
No! Let me fucking go! No!
玛德琳 马德琳
Maddy! Madeleine!
不要
No!
不 不要
No! No! No!
求你 别把我留在这里
No! Please, don`t leave me here!
控制住她了 不要
Got her! No!
不 求你了
No, please!
弗利博士
Dr. Foley!
放轻松 克莱尔
Just relax, Claire.
我发誓 我不再纠结了 也不会再伤害自己
I swear. I`m over… I won`t hurt myself.
我发誓
I swear.
不要
No!
你们这群傻逼
You fuckers!
你们这群杀千刀的傻逼
You blood fucking morons!
听我说
Listen to me!
他会把我们都杀掉的
He`ll kill us all!
你给她注射了什么
What did you give her?
10cc的美索比妥
Ten CCs of Methohexital.
足够让她平静了
Just enough to relax her.
她还有意识 但就是不能动弹
She`s conscious, but she just won`t be able to move.
你有看过她这样吗
Have you ever seen her like this?
不 从没有
No. Never.
有点闹心 但看到
It`s, uh, disturbing, but it`s fascinating to see.
这样大规模的癔症发作很有意思
this kind of mass hysteria in action.
其实挺惨的
It`s quite sad, really.
嘿 杰克怎么样了
Hey, how's Jake?
他还不错 多谢关心
He`s hanging in there, thanks.
你们的周年纪念就要到了吧
Don`t you guys have an anniversary coming up?
是啊
Yeah.
终于决定带他去见我的父母
Finally taking him to meet my parents.
马尔科姆出事了
It`s Malcolm.
我这边需要帮助 噢 天呐
I`m gonna need some help. Oh, God.
放松点 克莱尔 我马上就回来
Just… Just relax, Claire. I`ll be back in a bit.
不要
No.
压缩的
Compressed.
和我想的意思一样吗
Does that rnean what I think it rneans?
其实 我不知道
Seriously, I`m not sure.
不
No.
有时候我连自己都怕
Sometimes, I scare myself.
（又是恰奇做的吗？精神病院二人死亡）
你搞什么
What the fuck?
你以为只有一个我吗
You thought I was the only one?
等等 你在做什么
Wait! What are you doing?
要干什么
What`s going on?
是恰奇做的
Chucky did it.
那只是个意外 妮卡
It was an accident, Nica.
安吉拉也是被他所杀
He killed Angela, too.
我会假装你刚刚什么都没说
I`m gonna pretend you didn`t just say that.
还有马德琳 他在操控着她
And Madeleine, he`s manipulating her.
妮卡 她有幻想症
She`s delusional, Nica.
她和你一样 对娃娃产生幻觉
She's projecting onto the doll, just like you are.
我会证明一切的 弗利博士
I`m going to prove it, Dr. Foley.
还有
And you know what else?
那两个娃娃可能都是活的
I think both dolls are alive somehow.
快快醒来
Ade beaucoup Damballa.
我知道这听起来很荒唐
I know how crazy that sounds.
两个和一个活娃娃听起来都差不多疯狂 妮卡
No crazier than a single doll, Nica.
请告诉我你理解我的话
Please tell me you understand that.
另一个去哪了
What happened to the other one?
有人拿走了 我们会找出来的
Someone took it, and we`ll find it.
谁知道呢 也许就在你的房间里
Who knows, maybe in your room.
你是在怀疑我吗
You think it was me now?
妮卡 我跟你说实话在这个节骨眼上
To tell you the truth, Nica, at this point,
我真的不知道该去怀疑谁
I honestly don`t knowwhatto think.
弗利博士 我不是杀手
I`m not a killer, Dr. Foley.
而且我他妈没疯
And I`m not fucking crazy.
妮卡 我想要你为我做件事情
Nica, I want you to do something for me.
我想要催眠你
I wanna hypnotize you.
催眠我也不会有任何改变
Hypnotizing me is not gonna make a difference.
在过去可是很有用的一招
It`s been very useful in the past.
可以让大家都放心
And it might set our minds at ease.
没准能发现真相呢
We might find out what really happened.
妮卡 我不想把你送回洛克马
Nica, I don`t wanna have to send you back to Lochmoor.
催眠法能帮助人接受现实
Hypnosis helped you accept the truth.
你现在害怕接受现实吗
Now, are you afraid of the truth?
十分害怕
Terrified.
你也应该害怕
And you should be, too.
盯着灯光 妮卡
Keep your eyes on the light, Nica.
好了 妮卡 你感觉怎么样
All right, Nica, how do you feel?
还能接受
Receptive.
很好
As always, that`s good.
如果我告诉你在这里每个角落都有摄像头
What if I were to tell you there are cameras at H arrogate,
隐藏摄像头 到处都是 以至于你的每个动作都被记录下来了
hidden cameras, everywhere, and your every move has been recorded?
如果我说 妮卡
What if I were to tell you, Nica,
我们有你杀掉克莱尔和安吉拉的记录
there are recordings of you killing both Angela and Claire?
你会怎么回应
What would you say to that?
我无法对那样的证据做出辩解
Well, I couldn`t really argue with evidence like that.
你能想象到是如何杀了她们的 对吗 妮卡
You can picture yourself killing them, can`t you, Nica?
是的
Yes.
但现在 证据被抹去了
Now, what if that evidence then somehow got erased?
你说是谁会想要那么做
Who would wanna do that, do you think?
我
Me.
应该会第一个想到自己
would be my first guess.
我同意
I agree.
所以我们在谋杀和录影带还有你的负罪感
So we`re in agreement about the murders and the tapes.
方面达成共识
and your terrible guilt.
是的
Yes.
什么
What is it?
恰奇
Chucky.
他就在你后面
He`s right behind you.
我很怀念我们之间的这种小会面
I`ve missed these little sessions of ours.
你呢
Haven`t you?
没有
No.
你当然不怀念
No, of course not.
毕竟你什么都不记得
You can`t remember them.
这也许是最好的结果
Probably for the best.
我去
Holy shit!
居然有人说我变态
And they call me sick?
这个人简直就是穷凶极恶
This guy is… Is… Is diabolical!
他真是奇葩
I mean, what a piece of work.
我都有点嫉妒了
I`m actually a little envious.
你知道你想要杀他
You know you want to.
难道不是吗
Don`t you?
是的
Yes.
来吧 妮卡
Come on, Nica.
是时候加入我们了
Time to join the club.
妮卡姑姑
Auntie Nica.
爱丽丝
Alice?
我们等你好久了
We`ve been waiting for you.
弗利博士总说迟到的人是没有礼貌的
Dr. Foley always says late people are rude people.
这太不像他了
This is so unlike him.
迟来的弗利博士
The late Dr. Foley.
这么说还挺顺口的 不是吗 妮卡
Now that has a nice ring to it, doesn`t it, Nica?
希望他安然无恙
I sure hope nothing`s happened to him now.
只是不禁去想谁下一个死
It just kind of makes you wonder who`s next.
不是吗
Doesn`t it?
你是怎么了 马克
What is wrong with you, Mark?
我不叫马克
That`s not my name.
好吧 你他妈今天叫什么
Fine, what the hell is your name today?
查尔斯
It`s Charles.
我们应该见过
I think we`ve met.
马德琳
Madeleine?
我能抱抱他吗
Can I hold him?
我要把它放床上
I better put him down.
他有点不耐烦了
He`s getting a little cranky.
马德琳
Madeleine.
弗利博士
Dr. Foley.
你没事了
You're okay.
我的头简直快要炸了
I have a hell of a headache.
你不记得了吗
Don't you remember?
我记得你催眠了我 然后就
I remember you hypnotized me, and then…
其余的就有点模糊了
The rest is kind ofa blur.
你打了我 妮卡
You assaulted me, Nica.
他不是真的
He isn't real.
是你干的
It was you.
我很担心你这次复发
I am very concerned by this setback,
但此事如果你不说
but I am willing to keep my mouth shut about this incident.
我也不会说出去
if you are.
天啊
Oh, God.
你好
Hello?
你好 安迪
Hello, Andy.
你是谁
Who is this?
蒂凡尼
Tiffany.
詹尼弗
Jennifer.
我自己都记不清了
Even I lose track.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
我要去抓你
I'm coming for you.
还有他
And for him.
事实上 我们现在是三个人哟
Actually, there's three of us at the moment,
我们的队伍越来越壮大了
and the cult is growing all the time.
安迪 你想加入我们吗
Hey, Andy, you wanna join up?
去你的
Fuck you.
哦 我有一条来自恰奇的口信
Oh, I have a message from Chucky.
他说你会知道是什么意思的
He said you'll know what it means.
只有一个单词
It's just a single word.
他说 开膛破肚
He said, Disembowel.
安迪 现在你来说说是什么意思
Now, what do you suppose that means, Andy?
玛德琳
Madeleine?
Madeleine!
我从没停止过爱你
I never stopped loving you.
我永远都是你的朋友
I'm your friend to the end.
恰奇 男孩最好的朋友就是他的妈妈
You know, Chucky, a boy's best friend is his mother.
你想玩吗
Wanna play?
玛德琳
Madeleine!
玛德琳 你做了什么
Madeleine, what have you done?
什么
What?
玛德琳 你对你的孩子做了什么
What have you done to your baby, Madeleine?
这不是个孩子 只是个玩具娃娃
It's not a baby, it's just a doll.
你的孩子
Your baby.
约书亚
Joshua.
记得吗
Remember?
你对他做了什么 玛德琳
What did you do to him, Madeleine?
说出来
Say it.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我非常 非常抱歉
I'm so, so sorry.
不用对我说 玛德琳
Not to me, Madeleine.
跟他说
Say it to him.
我的小甜心 你能原谅我吗
My sweet angel, can you ever forgive me?
他总是哭
He just wouldn't stop crying.
无论我做什么 他都不停
No matter what I did, I couldn't make him stop.
那声音就像一块锋利的玻璃刺进我的头里
The sound was like a sharp piece of glass drilling into my head.
我是个恶母
I was a terrible mother.
我永远不能让他开心
I could never make him happy.
你没有杀掉他
You didn't kill him.
什么 妮卡 拜托
What? Nica, please.
他只是在假装
He's just pretending.
- 放开他 - 他还活着
- Leave him alone! - He's alive!
我喜欢被抱着
I like to be hugged.
我比谁都希望他是假死
More than anything, I wish that he was.
但希望也没有用 我现在是知道了
Wishing won't bring him back. I know that now.
给我吧
Come on.
那只是个娃娃
It's a doll.
他象征了你的内疚 马尔科姆的误会
And it's a powerful symbol of your guilt, Malcolm's confusion,
还有过去
and the past.
你们不觉得是时候永绝后患埋葬过去了吗
Now, don't you think it's time to bury the past once and for all?
毫无疑问 复活的希望和永恒的生命都将通过
In sure and certain hope of the resurrection unto eternal life.
我们的主耶稣基督
through our Lord Jesus Christ,
我们赞美我们爱戴的全能的神
we commend unto Almighty God our loved ones,
我们把自己的身体都献给大地
and we commit their bodies to the ground.
尘归尘 土归土 生终将死 灵终将灭
Earth to earth, ashes to ashes, dust to dust.
愿我们的主祝福他们 护佑他们
May the Lord bless them and keep them.
并将他的光照耀在他们身上
and shine His light down upon them.
给他们以恩惠 给他们以平和
and be gracious unto them and give them peace.
阿门
Amen.
你还是不信 对吧
You're not buying it, are you?
不信
Nope.
他还会回来的
He'll be back.
他总能回来
He always comes back.
（联邦快递）
拜访时间结束了 先生
Visiting hours are over, sir.
麻烦你掉头
Gonna have to ask you to turn around.
我要立刻见弗利医生或者是妮卡·皮尔斯
I need to see Dr. Foley, or Nica Pierce, right away.
好吧 你可以打电话预约一下时间
Well, you can call and make an appointment.
不 这是紧急情况
No, this is an emergency.
我明白 但现在 请你回到你的车里
I bet, but now, please, just get back in your car.
然后调头开走 好吗
and turn it around, all right?
那我要入院
Okay, then I wanna commit myself.
赶紧他妈的离开这里 马上
Get the hell out of here! Right now!
晚安咯
Night-night.
这些是刚刚寄给你的 弗利医生
This just came for you, Dr. Foley.
谁寄来的
Who's it from?
没有写
Doesn't say.
他头发怎么了
What happened to his hair?
为什么会有人寄这个给我
Why would anyone send this to me?
现在 我们有更重要的事情要担心
You know, we've got way more important things to worry about right now.
- 先去查房吧 - 好的
- Let's get on our rounds. - Yeah.
不能留鞋带
No shoelaces.
这是他仅剩的东西了
It's all I have left of him.
弗利医生把你列入自杀监管名单了
Dr. Foley put you on suicide watch.
如果死了能见到他 我会做的
You know, I'd do it if I thought I could see him again.
但是自杀不能去天堂 对吗
But suicides don't go to heaven, do they?
玛德琳 我不知道
I don't know, Madeleine.
我只知道我自己有两个孩子
I just know I have two children of my own,
而我会做任何事情来确保他们安全
and I'd do anything to keep them safe.
你会为了他们杀人吗
Would you kill for them if it was for their own good?
你那么爱他们吗
Do you love them that much?
阿什利护士 请到护士站来一趟
Nurse Ashley, please report to the nurses' station.
我会每15分钟查看你一趟
I'll be checking on you every 15 minutes.
你好 宝宝
Hi, baby.
他们不会理解我们的
They just don't get us.
永远不会理解的
And they never will.
母爱长存
A mother's love never dies.
杀死孩子的时候也爱着
Not even when she kills it.
拜托
Now, please,
最后一次
one last time,
回到妈妈身边吧
come to Mommy.
会很疼吗
Will it hurt?
我会尽力避免的
I'll do my best.
今天可真不是个好日子 对吧 医生
Well, you're having a bad day, aren't you, Doc?
阿什利 带他回病床
Ashley, put him to bed.
弗利医生 我觉得我不能再干下去了
Dr. Foley, I don't think I can do this anymore.
- 什么 - 太诡异了
- What? - It's too much.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
回床上去 马尔科姆
Go to bed, Malcolm.
好的
Sure.
把这东西扔了
Get rid of it.
好的 先生
Yes, sir.
妮卡
Nica?
你是怎么进来的
How did you get in here?
你猜
Take a fucking guess.
如果这是开玩笑 今天可不是时候
If this is a joke, this is not a good day for it.
是恰奇干得
It was Chucky.
为什么我总爱上疯子
Why do I always fall for the crazy ones?
玛德琳死了
Madeleine's dead.
是恰奇干的
Chucky did it.
不
No.
她是自杀的
She killed herself.
她把它挖了出来还自残
She dug him up and mutilated herself.
造成恰奇干的假象
so it looked like Chucky did it.
不
No.
除非全是你杀的 妮卡
Unless you killed them all, Nica.
你知道 这对我来说并不重要
You know, it doesn't really matter to me.
因为 无论哪种方式 都能写一本好书
because, either way, it's gonna make a hell of a book.
但是现在 你必须要回到洛克马
But now, you're gonna have to go back to Lochmoor.
太可怜了 毕竟在这里 我可以给你
It's too bad, because here, I could've given you.
很多私人关心
so much more personal attention.
他也会杀了你
He's gonna kill you, too.
你肯定会死的
You're gonna die,
而我会告诉大家真正的你
and I'm gonna tell everybody about you.
你被诊断为精神分裂症
You`re a diagnosed schizophrenic.
并且还是杀害五个人的凶手 这还只是我们目前所知的
and a murderess of five people, that we know of.
没人会听你的
No one`s going to listen to you.
真是拿他没办法
I just can`t with this guy!
我不知道是该学他还是杀掉他
I don`t know whether to kill him or just take notes.
你再来做一次
Now, we`re gonna try this again.
我不会杀人
I`m not a killer.
还不是而已
Not yet.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
他到了
He`s here.
真够墨迹的
Took him long enough.
蠢孩子
Stupid kid.
安迪已经不是孩子了
Andy`s not a kid anymore.
你想说什么
So what`s your point?
我只是说 我们理应小心行事
I`m just saying, it behooves us to watch our step.
理应 听听你自己的话
Behooves. Listen to you.
你听起来像是汉尼拔·莱克特
You sound like Hannibal Lecter.
真不敢相信他们取消了那个节目
Can`t believe they canceled that show.
他是从哪冒出来的
Where'd he come from?
谁在乎 唤醒他
Who cares? Wake him up.
伟大的丹巴拉
Ade beaucoup Damballa.
我乞求你 赐予我力量
Give me the power, I beg of you!
你脑袋怎么了
What the hell happened to you?
我喜欢做我自己
You know, I love being me.
我喜欢我的工作
And I love my job.
尤其是在最后一刻
Especially the look on my victim`s face.
当他们意识到
when they realize, in that final moment,
这一切都在真实发生的时候的表情
that it`s all really happening.
一个小孩的玩具用一把码尺活活把人打死
A children`s toy is actually beating them to death with a yardstick!
或者把他们点着
Or setting them on fire.
或者把他们开膛破肚
Eviscerating them.
这都是真实的案例
All actual examples.
几年前 我在
A few years ago, I came across this groovy new spell.
傻瓜巫毒术网站上找到的这条绝妙的咒语改变了一切
on VoodooForDummies.com that changed everything.
现在 我成为我
Now, I can be me.
我 和我
And me. And me.
理论上讲 可以成为任何有两条腿和
And theoretically, anyone or anything.
一个能捅人的胳膊
with two legs and a hand for stabbing.
比如爱丽丝
Like Alice.
一开始很有趣
It was fun for a while.
人们对可爱的小女孩的信任几乎和对可爱的玩偶一样深
People trust cute little girls almost as much as cute little dolls,
但是小女儿在受害者还手的时候会受伤
but little girls can get hurt when their victims try to fight back.
然后她们就不那么可爱了
Then they ain`t so cute anymore.
快跑
Run!
不
No.
No!
我钻他的时候他的表情最有意思了
He made the funniest face when I drilled him!
你看到我把他的肚皮划开时候的热气了吗
Did you see the steam when I sliced open his guts?
我从没感觉如此充满活力
I`ve never felt so alive!
是啊 你也才活了两分钟
Yeah, well, you`ve been alive for, like, two minutes.
欢迎加入 伙计
Welcome to the cult, pal.
好的 谢谢 你们最棒了
Right. Thanks. You guys are the best.
我要去杀安迪
Now, I`m gonna go kill Andy.
不 我想杀安迪 这是我应得的
No, I wanna kill Andy. I earned it.
我今天受得够多了
I`ve been through a lot today.
你今天还吸奶奶了 看看我都经历了些什么
You got to suck titty today. Look what happened to me.
喂 看看我的头发
Hello? Look at my hair.
哦 该死 你赢了
Oh, shit. You win.
绝对的 抱歉 伙计 你去好好收拾他
Absolutely. Sorry, pal. You go fuck him up real good.
玩的愉快
Have fun.
你 守好门
You, guard the door.
谁要想进来就把他杀掉
Kill anyone that tries to get in.
好的
Right.
我来处理她
I`ll take care of her.
樱桃甜筒
Cherry snow cone.
真美味
Yummy.
快动手吧
Just fucking do it already.
让我解脱
Get it over with.
如果我想让你死 你早就死翘翘了
If I wanted you dead, you`d be tits-up by now.
我是不会杀你的 妮卡
I was never gonna kill you, Nica.
相信我 有比死更可怕的事
Believe me, there`s worse things than death.
伟大的丹巴拉
Ade beaucoup Damballa.
我乞求你 给予我力量
Give me all the power, I beg of you!
你好啊 医生
Hiya, Doc.
被超自然邪灵附身还是有好处的
There`s definitely perks to being supernaturally possessed.
这是替妮卡踩的
This is for Nica.
我成功了
I did it.
我杀了她
I killed her.
我让那个婊子得到了应有的下场
I gave that bitch what she deserved.
不 你没有
No, you didn`t.
我杀了她
I killed her.
因为我是查尔斯
Because I`m Charles!
做梦吧 混球
In your dreams, asshole.
我是查尔斯
I`m Charles.
但是所有人都叫我恰奇
But everybody calls me Chucky.
没人那么叫我
Nobody calls me that.
不 等 等一下
No, wait a… Wait a minute.
我现在是谁
Who am I now?
你就是个模仿者 真变态
You`re a fucking poser. You`re sick.
还不像我那么搞笑
And not in the fun way like me.
妮卡
Nica?
妮卡在睡觉
Nica`s taking a nap.
我会确保她永远也醒不来
And I`m gonna make sure she never wakes up.
我只想变成有意义的人
I just wanna be someone who matters.
但是我不是马克 我不是迈克尔
But I`m not Mark. I`m not Michael. I`m…
我只是马尔科姆
I`m just Malcolm.
该死的马尔科姆
Fucking Multiple Malcolm.
似乎你脑子里很挤啊
Sounds like it`s getting pretty crowded in there.
我还能听到他
I can hear him.
我还能听到恰奇在我的脑袋里
I can still hear Chucky inside my head!
这个地方可真有趣
And it was such a nice place to visit.
安迪·巴克利 真意外啊
Andy Barclay, as I live and breathe.
不
No!
游戏结束 混球
This is the end, fucker!
是你寄的我吗
You sent me?
多谢你来找我 省了我不少麻烦
Thanks for coming after me. You saved me the trouble.
去你的
Fuck you!
你杀了我 就等于杀了她
You kill me, you kill her.
想想看吧
Think about it.
没错 输家才思考
Yeah, thinking is for losers.
封锁 此设施进入封锁状态
Lockdown. The facility is now on lockdown.
病人请立即回到病房
Patients to your rooms, immediately.
碰到就是你了 伙计
Tag, you`re it, pal.
不
No!
保安 西侧走廊
Security, west hail.
Security, code one in west hail.
你好 娃娃脸
Hey, sweet-face.
很高兴看到你又变回人了
Good to see you back on your feet.
你看起来很不错 蒂芙
You look great, Tiff.
和以前不一样了
So this is different.
可能吧
I don`t know.
我能接受
Works for me.
不过有些事还是没变
Some things never change, though.
真正的经典永不过时
!!A true classic never goes out of style.!!
你和我说过一次 在扎了一个男的39刀之后
You said that to me once, after stabbing a man 39 times.
怎么了
What?
我只是为爱丽丝感到难过
I was just feeling bad about Alice.
有她在身边感觉很不错
It was kind of nice, having Alice around, you know?
才不 去她的
Nah, fuck that kid.
凯尔
Kyle?
安迪派我来的
Andy sent me.
我们好好玩玩
We`re gonna have some fun.